Raza Ali

M: +91.967.683.1928
E: raza.ali@writeme.com
W: www.mindtuner.info





Dear Sir/Madam,

I came across your job posting which indicated requirements that closely match my background and expertise. Please refer to my Resume for my detailed work experience and qualifications.

As a certified trainer from MSI, U.S.A (CTCTM) with an experience of over a decade in Canada, India, and UAE in various roles such as student Counselling, English language Coaching, Business Development and more. I am also proficient in delivering a wide range of Technical and Soft-skills Training modules.

My expertise lies in Maximizing Performance, Career Coaching, and Student Development to name a few. My experience spans over 12 industries and over the years I have acquired a 'Master Certificate in Leadership Management' from MCM, U.S.A., along with TTT and NLP certifications.

Some of the major roles I have undertaken in Canada, UAE and India include:

- Student Counsellor Abroad Education & Career Guidance
- Trainer in Career Planning, English Language & Performance Mgmt.
- Business Development and Customer Service
- Conference and Event Management From inception till delivery



My Training techniques involve research-based visual and interactive approach, along with a 'Stand-Up' delivery style combined with real-life applications. The training also involves NLP techniques for enhanced learning and knowledge retention.

Some of my Training/Coaching strengths include:

- 1. Signature Training Content: Disruptive Applications, Variant & Lateral Thinking, etc.
- 2. Unique Training Technique [Cook Book Approach]
- 3. Informal coaching approach for enhanced comfort learning
- 4. VARK and NLP based coaching

Some of the organizations I have worked with in the past include:

















With an excellent training track record in Training and Development, I am positioned to exceed your expectations. I look forward to a meeting to showcase how my skills can be maximized for this role. Thank you.

Raza Ali



RAZA ALI CERTIFIED TRAINER

Contact

🥋 Hyderabad, India

naza.ali@writeme.com

+ 91.967.683.1928

www.mindtuner.info

Certifications

CORPORATE TRAINER CERTIFIED Management & Strategy Institute

TRAIN THE TRAINER Total Success Training Institute

CERTIFIED TRAINER LEADERSHIP MANAGEMENT Master Class Management

CERTIFIED NLP PRACTITIONER P. A. NLP Master Trainer

Education

BACHLORS OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION Thompson Rivers University 2010 | BC, Canada

DIPLOMA IN TEACHING SKILLS FOR EDUCATORS Alison Certified Training Institute 2017 | Dubai, UAE

DIPLOMA IN EDUCATIONAL **PSYCHOLOGY** Alison Certified Training Institute 2017 | Dubai, UAE

"I believe achieving excellence is a lifelong process, in order to attain it we must constantly improve ourselves and our surroundings to reach our maximum potential"

Areas Of Expertise

- Career Counseling
- English Coaching
- Academic Training
- Corporate Training
- IELTS/PTE Coaching
- Performance Mamt.
- Talent Management
- Business Development
 Quality/Service Mgmt.
- Integrated Marketing
- Event Hosting
- Student Counselling
- Web Designing
- Conference Production
- Graphic Designing

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- 10+ years of Performance Training & Career Coaching experience
- Launched 40+ signature training modules for Corporates, Universities & Schools
- Trained and Counselled 1000+ students worldwide
- Conducted signature IELTS training with average 7 band score
- Acquired over 5 years of experience in the Conferencing sector
- Hosted and facilitated more than 50 high-profile events globally

WORK EXPERIENCE | Hyderabad, India

Performance Trainer | Language and Career Jan. 2019 – Present

Key Activities Include:

- Conducted signature IELTS training with VARK and NLP Techniques
- Launched career-focused training on CV building and Interview skills
- Organized academic performance training using IG Techniques

Project IA | Interface Alliances Global Education Jul. 2019 - Dec. 2019 Manager - Student Experience & Training

Key Activities Include:

- Counselling students on different destinations to study abroad
- Manage quality assurance for the entire student counselling process
- Conducted IELTS training for students with VARK and NLP Techniques
- Redesigned the entire brand-image and marketing & Sales strategy

WORK EXPERIENCE | Dubai, UAE

Mind Tuner Consulting

Jan. 2018 - Nov. 2018

Student Development Specialist | Performance Trainer

Key Activities Include:

- Launched exclusive training modules for Student Career Development
- Launched hybrid coaching modules for Talent and Passion Management
- Shepherded in depth career guidance sessions and seminars for students

Major Project | Al Wahda School Teaching Skills Trainer | Student Counselor

Feb. 2016 - Dec. 2017

Kev Activities Include:

- Conducted Interactive Training on Soft-Skills for 250+ teachers
- Conducted in-depth career guidance sessions and seminars for students
- Established 'Intelligence Grafting' Techniques for enhanced learning

Speaker

THE GREAT TIMES OF INDIA CAREER FAIR Host and Speaker 2017 | Dubai, U.A.E.

DUBAI AMERICAN ACADEMY
CAREER CONFERENCE
Disruptive Applications
for Career Development
2018 | Dubai, UAE

MIDDLESEX UNIVERSITY Maximizing Career Horizons 2016 | Dubai, UAE

Software Skills

Adobe Suite

MS Office

WordPress

Hobbies







Personal Details

DATE OF BIRTH May 21st, 1986

NATIONALITY Indian

VALID DRIVER LICENSE India & U.A.E.

NATIVE SPEAKER FLUENCY English, Hindi, Urdu

TOTAL YEARS OF EXPERIENCE Canada, U.A.E. & INDIA 12 Years

WORK EXPERIENCE | Dubai, UAE

Sigmoid Knowledge Development Consultancy Corporate and Academic Trainer | On-site host Jan. 2014 – Nov. 2015

Key Activities Include:

- Conducted career coaching sessions for schools & universities
- Spearhead technical corporate training on Oil & Gas, Sales & Marketing
- Researched and developed technical conference programs in Oil & Gas

Praxis Global Research (Oil & Gas)

May 2010 - Dec. 2013

Marketing Manager | Global In-House Trainer

Key Activities Include:

- Led an 8-member team managing product development for all branches
- Liaising with media partners, sponsors, on-site team for all global events
- Successfully launched 'Technical Analysis Branch' [TAB] which aimed to train all employees to gain proficiency in the technical Oil and Gas Processes
- Launched in-house tele sales training modules for enhanced sales tactics

WORK EXPERIENCE | B.C., Canada

Nando's Restaurant (Abbotsford & Richmond) Jan. 2009 – April 2010

General Manager

Pitt Meadows Cranberry Farm (Vancouver) Feb. 2008 – Nov. 2008

Procurement Manager & Trainer

Super 8 Motel (Kamloops) Dec. 2006 - Jan. 2008

Brand Executive

Volunteer Work | B.C., Canada

Royal Inland Hospital (Kamloops) March – Nov. 2006

Head of Volunteer Committee

Advancing Canadian Entrepreneurs (Kamloops) Oct. 2005 – Dec. 2006

Sr. Project Manager

Co-curricular Achievements

Indian Student Association | President and Co-founder | TRU Canada TRU Table Tennis Club | Founder and Tournament Manager Interuniversity Table Tennis Tournament, U.A.E. | Silver Medalist | Singles '05